Fatemeh Rahimi

NI P Researcher



CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am an NLP Researcher who has experience with several NLP downstream tasks (Classification, regression, summarization, ranking). I am seeking a position to develop creative solutions for real-world problems using traditional and cuttingedge ML/DL solutions. I have 7+ years of experience in software development and data science projects in total.



Selected Projects

Using Multi-task Learning to improve Multi-label classifications task

Dalhousie University, Halifax, Canada/ March 2020 - now

- Master's Thesis
- Developing a library for multi-tasking architectures using Python, PyTorch, Hugging Face libraries, and MLflow Tracking
- Using language pre-trained models such as BERT, BioBERT, and RoBERTa

Learn Faster and Forget Slower via FAST and Stable Task Adaptation for pretrained language models

Dalhousie University, Halifax, Canada/ May 2020 - now

- Improving the fine-tunning algorithm of pre-trained language model
- Developing with Python, PyTorch, Hugging Face libraries, and MLflow Tracking
- Team project

Information Retrieval of covid-19 academic papers using language models

Dalhousie University, Halifax, Canada/ April 2020 - now

- Using unsupervised fine-tunning and Siamese network to train the T5 model for finding related documents to a query
- Dataset is from the TREC-COVID competition
- Team project

More projects and their details are listed in my personal website.



EXPERIENCE

Intern NLP Researcher Imagia, Montreal, Canada.

Nov 2020 - now

- Developed traditional and state-of-the-art solutions to solve NLP related problems using pre-trained language models
- Implemented recent research with biomedical domain corpus

Research Assistant (Deep Learning, NLP)

Dalhousie University, Halifax, Canada/ March 2019 - now

- Developing SOTA Deep Language models research (Transfer learning in NLP)
- Working under the supervision of Dr. Milios and Dr. Matwin
- Leveraged my knowledge of Python to develop a CLI tool for multi-task learning, Multi-label classification using existing infrastructures.

Data Analyst

Ayten, Shiraz, Iran/Aug 2018 - Feb 2019

- Part of social network analysis team, worked with python, neo4j, and MongoDB
- Used Scrum (Software Development framework)



CONTACT

Email:

Fateme.rhmi@gmail.com

Phone:

+1 (782) 414-7447

Address:

Halifax, Nova Scotia

LinkedIn:

https://linkedin.com/in/fatemehrahimi

GitHub:

https://github.com/fatemerhmi

Personal Website:

https://fatemerhmi.github.io/



EDUCATION

M.S. / Computer Science

Dalhousie University, Halifax, Canada May 2019 - April 2021

GPA: 4.07 (Out of 4.3)

B.S. / Software Engineering

Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran

Sep 2013 - Feb 2018

GPA: 16.11(out of 20)



HARD SKILLS

Python, Java, C

Numpy, scikit-learn, pandas, Mathplotlib

PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Hugging Face Transformers, MLflow

MySQL, Neo4j, MongoDB

Git, Window, Linux



SOFT

Self-motivated

Hard working

Team Player

Problem-Solving

Public Speaking

Research oriented

Communication skills